Marco Jones

Contact Details

Mobile: +44(0)751 498 1020 Languages: English (native), Italian (fluent),

Residence: Enfield, UK Portuguese (BR, B1)
Email: Marco.Jones1@proton.me Github: Marcoj776

Links: My website, Link Hub

Key Skills

• React JS, Remix, Typescript, Tailwind, HTML, PHP/Laravel, Magento, Shopify, WordPress

 CI/CD: serverless hosting on fly.io, automated testing with: Cypress, Jest, and Mocking (MSW), all executed via GitHub Actions

• Database: Prisma, SQL, SQLite, MySQL

Work History

Frontend Developer (React), KTM Online: Nov 2022 – Sep 24 reference: stuart.harvey@ktmonline.co.uk Upgraded a custom-built PHP/JQuery/Vue e-commerce website into an interactive and animated React SPA to greatly improve: user experience, performance, and conversion rate. Ensured code correctness by applying strict Typescript rules, even for asynchronous code, which reduced later discovered bugs. Worked closely with stakeholders to envision a UX goal, plan development, and maintain project oversight during remote work. Cooperating with the in-house UI designer, built a long-term UI design language in order to guide efficient development of reusable components and adjustable theming for future marketing campaigns.

Front-end developer, Filoblu: Sept 2019 – August 2022 reference: daniele.balzano@filoblu.com
Working in an agile environment alongside creative, UX, and project management to implement practical, user-friendly customer experiences with a variety of major online retailers compatible for Chromium and Safari browsers on all platforms. I was responsible for taking ownership of and regularly reporting on tickets assigned to me for website development and maintenance, and in stakeholder management for bug resolution and for developing new feature on request. This required precise communication and remote teamwork as parties were geographically separated and spread over two languages. In my first 6 months I became proficient in HTML, CSS, and JS/React for Magento projects, and became the lead developer for the Shopify and VTEX websites designed by FiloBlu, taking complete ownership of frontend management and analysis.

Freelance and self-study, Dec 2021 – Present reference: <u>qo to my website</u>

Developed a responsive React frontend for a client looking to build an online honey shop with Bitcoin payments. This required use of the BTCpayserver API as well as responding to payment confirmation. My client was impressed with my directness and energy in moving the project forward with minimal development time to meeting their requirements so they could get their store online and begin servicing customers. Studying with Kent C. Dodds' course, www.EpicReact.dev, gave me the confidence to take on a freelance project and use best practises of React development.

Data Analyst, Marston Holdings, 2017-2019

Produced new data reports for key stakeholders across the group. Gradually centralising all reports and automating them using advanced level Excel and VBA skills that I developed. I was responsible for gathering requirements and extending the requirements where I saw fit. Given the regular schedule of reporting, I had to strictly organise my work fixed schedule whilst continually taking on more responsibility.

Personal statement

An analytical and technically proficient developer with values and skills well aligned to writing clean and efficient code. My Computer Science degree has given me a strong focus on logical, efficient, and robust development techniques. I am self-motivated, inquisitive, and able to learn new systems quickly and independently. From my experience at FiloBlu I understand the value in cooperation of creative and technical to achieve interesting and responsive apps. From my work at FiloBlu I have a track record of being able to self-manage effectively and learn both independently and from the team around me skills (and languages) necessary.

Education

University of York – BEng Computer science June 2016 3rd Year Modules:

Machine Learning Application – Developing solutions to graphical models and recognition with Bayesian, regression and manifold learning techniques from their mathematical foundations.

Programming Correctness by Construction -

Using discrete mathematics to formulate specifications and refinements for programs and processes to design programs from a logical base. Design a program from first principles to reduce malfunctions and security flaws

Multi-Agent Interaction in Games – Exploring mathematics of strategy in games to guarantee optimal effectiveness for agents in various situations.

Introduction to Neural Networks – training and analysing neural networks to data to solve nonlinear classification problems.

Final year project, Calculating a Correct Compiler – Constructed a Haskell compiler for my own small programming language, using an equational reasoning technique to simultaneously prove its function

Computing and Technical skills

Paradigms: Functional, Object-oriented, Test-driven, Asynchronous, Blockchain

Languages: Solidity, React, JavaScript, Node, PHP, HTML, CSS, Python, Haskell, SQL, VBA

Operating Systems: Windows, Gnu, Android, Linux